[{"question":"Which of the following is a transporting tube leading from the bladder which brings urine outside the body via penis?","a":" Ureter ","b":"Epididymis","c":"Ejaculatory Duct","d":"Urethral Meatus","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Sperms produce an enzymatic substance for dissolving egg coverings. It is called","a":"Hyaluronic acid ","b":"Hyaluronidase","c":"Androgamone","d":"Diastase","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"10 oogonia yield 10 primary cocytes, then how many ova are produced on completion of oogenesis?","a":"5","b":"10","c":"20","d":"40","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Ovulation or release of ovum occurs on day of menstual cycle.","a":"8-10 day","b":"12-14 Day","c":"4-14 Day","d":"Last Two Days.","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which one of the following is the most likely root cause for menstruation not taking place at regular cycling in human female?","a":"Maintenance of the hypertrophical endometrial lining.","b":"Maintenance of high concentration of sex hormones in the blood stream.","c":"Retention of well developed corpus luteum.","d":"Fertilisation of the ovum.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the mammalian blastocvst is not true?","a":"The trophoblast gives rise to the embryo proper.","b":"Maternal genes are expressed during cleavage.","c":"The blastocyst implants in the mother's uterus.","d":"Early mammalian development is slow.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Menstruation results in the discharge of:","a":"the cornus luteum of the uterus.","b":"surface cells from the vagina.","c":"blood from the outer surface of the uterus.","d":"the endometrial lining","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which one of the following is the precise site of embryo implantation in a normal pregnancy?","a":"Endomrtrium","b":"Vagina ","c":"Oviduct","d":"Cervix","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Frollicular atresia is:","a":"formation of corpus luteum.","b":"degeneration of follicles till puberty.","c":"formation of Graafian follicle.","d":"increase in number of follicles.","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The type of placenta found in human beings is:","a":"Diffuse ","b":"Zonary","c":"Cotyledonary","d":"Discoidal","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"The role of the corpus luteum and the hormones it produces ends:","a":"at the time of embryonic implantation in the uterus.","b":"with the formation of the placenta.","c":"during the second trimester of pregnancy.","d":"just prior to parturition.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following statements regardi sertoli cell is correct?","a":"It is found in seminiferous tubule and seen testosterone hormone.","b":"It is a place where spermatozoa is concentrat and stored until ejaculation.","c":"It secretes spermatozoa activating substan like fructose, citrate, inositol, prostaglanc and protein.","d":"It is found in seminiferous tubule function as nurse cells for differentiati spermatozoil.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which one of the following statements incorrect about menstruation?","a":"During normal menstruation, about 40 ml blood is lost.","b":"The menstrual fluid can ensily elot.","c":"At menopause in the female, there is especially abrupt increase in gonadotropie hormones.","d":"The beginning of the cycle of menstruation is called menarche.","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which of the following best represents the normal path of a sperm cell as it makes its way from the point of entry into the female's reproductive tract to the place where fertilisation typically occurs?","a":"Cervix, vagina, ovary, oviduct","b":"Vagina, cervix, uterus, oviduct","c":"Uterus, cervix, vagina, oviduct","d":"Vagina, uterus, cervix, oviduct","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"\"A\" cells start division and enter in \"B\" stage of meiotic division and get temporarily *C* at this stage, called \"D\". Identify A, B, C and D.","a":"A: Oogonia; B: Metaphase I; C: Arrested; D: Primary oocyte.","b":"A: Oogonia; B: Anaphase I; C: Released; D: Secondary oocyte.","c":"A: Oogonia; B: Prophase I; C: Arrested; D: Primary oocyte.","d":"A: Oogonia; B: Telophase I; C: Released; D: Secondary cocyte.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Assume 2n =12 in a hypothetical species. In gametogenesis, the number of chromosomes in a spermatid would be and in a first polar body would be____and in polar boby would be _____ .","a":"3,3 ","b":"3,6","c":"6,3","d":"6,6","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which of the following groups of cells in the male gonad represent haploid cells?","a":"Spermatogonial cells ","b":"Germinal Epithelial Cells","c":"Secondary spermatocytes","d":"Primary spermatocytes","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Milk secreted from the cells of alveoli of mammary lobes reaches nipple through lactiferous duct (L), mammary duct (M), mammary tubule (T) and mammary ampulla (A). Choose the option which shows the correct order.","a":"TMAL ","b":"MTLA","c":"MTAL","d":"ATMI","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"For approximately how long during the human female's menstrual cycle are progesterone concentrations high enough to maintain the uterus in a proper condition for pregnancy?","a":"All of the cycle","b":"None of the cycle","c":"During the first half of the cycle","d":"During the second half of the cycle","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Shortest phase in the menstriation evcle of women is:","a":"Menses","b":"Luteal phase","c":"Ovulatory Phase ","d":"Follicular Phase","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which gland releases a small amount of fluid just prior to ejaculation to decrease acidity in the urethra caused by urine?","a":"Prostate Critical Thinking ","b":"GlansPenis","c":"Seminal Vesicle ","d":"Bulbourethral Gland","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"The head of mature mammalian sperm is made of:","a":"An acrosome ","b":" Two centrioles and an axial filament ","c":"Elongated Nucleus Covered By Acrosome","d":" Nucleus, Acrosome, Cytoplasm Mitochondrial Sheath","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"A sac shaped like an upside down pear with 3 thick lining and muscles in the pelvic are where a fertilised egg or zygote comes to grow into a baby is called ____.","a":"Oviduct ","b":"Uterus","c":"Vagina","d":"Vulva","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Cleavage in the fertilised egg of humans:","a":"starts in uterus ","b":"Is Meroblastic","c":"Starts When Egg Is In Fallopian Tube ","d":"Is Discoidal","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Identica twins regult when:","a":"the zygote divides and the daughter cells split and develop independently.","b":"two eggs with identical genetic material are fertilised, each by a different sperm.","c":"an embryo splits before cellular differentiation has occurred.","d":"Both (a) and (c)","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Keeping a normal, sexually mature woman in her mid-twenties on continuous high doses of progesterone will:","a":"cause her to ovulate repeatedly within each menstrual cycle.","b":"stimulate the production of mature follicles.","c":"prevent her from producing mature follicles and ovulating.","d":"cause the endometrial lining of her uterus to slough off.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following is the first change that occurs to the zygote after fertilisation?","a":"It divides to form a hollow ball of cells, called the blastocyst.","b":"It begins to secrete the hormones.","c":"It contacts the endometrial wall of the uterus and becomes buried inside it.","d":"It initiates the formation of a placenta.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"The human embryo, with 8 to 16 blastomere is called:","a":"Morula ","b":"Blastula","c":"Gastrula","d":"Foetus","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"In males, testes are contained in the scrotal sacs because:","a":"other organs do not make space for the testes in the abdominal cavity.","b":"testes in the abdomen will hamper maturation of sperms.","c":"it provides temperature that is slightly lower than body temperature required for formation of functional sperms.","d":"it facilitates ejaculation.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Ejaculation of human male contains about 200 - 300 million sperms, of which for normal fertility____ % sperms must have normal shape and size and at least____ % must show energetic motility.","a":"40,60","b":"50,50","c":"60,40","d":"30,70","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Polar body is produced during the formation of:","a":"Sperm ","b":"Secondary Oocyte","c":"Oogonium","d":"Spermatocytes","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"A couple have been trying to conceive a child for over a year without success. Recently, the man's doctor informed him that his seminal vesicles are defective. This means that:","a":"the man makes functional sperm but they are not delivered because he is unable to ejaculate.","b":"the man's sperm lack functional flagella","c":"the fluid needed to lubricate the man's urethra for easier sperm travel is defective.","d":"the man's semen lacks the fructose fuel needed for the sperm to swim.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which of the following statement regarding human development is correct?","a":"Ovulation occurs at primary oocyte stage.","b":"Chorion develops from inner cell mass.","c":"Embryonic disc develops from trophoblast.","d":"Primitive streak is formed in the post part of the embryonic shield.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"All of the following statements concerning pregnancy are accurate except:","a":"the detection of human chorionic gonadotropin in the urine forms the basis for pregnancy tests.","b":"the cyclic release of pituitary gonadotropins and ovarian steroids is continued.","c":"the mammary gland tissue of the pregnant woman is stimulated to develop by placental hormones.","d":"the corpus luteum of pregnancy maintains the uterus until the placenta is well established.","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Spermiogenesis/Spermatogenesis is the transformation of :","a":"spermatogonium into primary spermatocyte.","b":"spermatogonium into functional spermatozoa.","c":"primary spermatocytes into secondary spermatocytes.","d":"spermatids into spermatozoa.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which of the following would you expect, if you compared the genetic makeup of an animal produced by parthenogenesis with that of its mother?","a":"About 100 percent genetic similarity","b":"About 50 percent genetic similarity","c":"No genetic similarity","d":"Parthenogenetic animals have no mother","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"By the end of how many weeks, major organ system are formed during the embryonic development?","a":"4 weeks ","b":" 8 Weeks","c":" 12 Weeks","d":"24 Weeks","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"From which embryonic structure does vertebral column develop?","a":"Notochord ","b":"Nerve Cord ","c":"Dermis","d":"Mesodermal Somites","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"When a bird lays a fertilised egg, the embryo is in:","a":"Zygote stage ","b":"Blastula Stage ","c":"Early Gastrula Stage ","d":"Complete Gastrula Stage","hint":"","correct":"c"}]